this exercise gives us
a local variable numbers referencing an
array of numbers one through five
we've been instructed to use the array
map method
to iterate over this numbers array and
return
a new array with each number doubled
we will assign the returned array to a
variable named
doubled numbers and print its value
using p
again iteration is a very common task
and when you need to transform an array
as you iterate through it
you should use array map
map will return a new array
with the elements transformed based on
the return value of the block
this might all sound a little bit
confusing so let's see it in action
[Music]
we know we need to call the map method
on our numbers array
and map accepts a block and uses the
return value of this block
[Music]
let's call our block parameter number
now as map iterates through this array
each element will be passed to the block
and assigned to the block parameter
number which is a variable local to this
block
for now let's just put number on line
four
and assign the return value of this
method call
[Music]
to the variable doubled numbers
we'll output doubled numbers with p and
just see what we've got
and you see an array that looks exactly
the same as the original array that we
called map on
map returns a new array with the
elements
transformed based on the return value of
its block
now in this case the return value of the
block
is the original number that we passed
into the block
that's why our new array doubled numbers
has the same elements
as the original array numbers
so in order to transform the elements of
our array
we need to change the return value of
our block
recall that the return value of this
block is going to be
the evaluated result of the last line
executed
in this case line 4 will be the last and
only line executed in this block
the evaluated result of multiplying
number
by 2 will be double the original number
that new number will be returned from
the block and will become
an element of our new transformed array
so let's run our code now and see what
the values of our doubled numbers array
are and this time we see the expected
transformation
so keep the array map method in mind
when you need to
transform an array as you iterate
through it
and be aware of how map uses the return
value of its block
you